// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Why is Earth called 'the living planet?'",
    answer: "D. All of the above",
    options: [
      "A. It sustains life.",
      "B. It has atmosphere.",
      "C. It has water at the surface.",
      "D. All of the above",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which among the set of planets are called terrestrial?",
    answer: "B. Mercury, Venus, Mars, Earth",
    options: [
      "A. Jupiter, Neptune, Uranus",
      "B. Mercury, Venus, Mars, Earth",
      "C. Earth, Venus, Mars, Jupiter",
      "D. Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What makes the planet Earth habitable compared to other planets?",
    answer: "D. It has liquid water",
    options: [
      "A. It has soil.",
      "B. It has trees.",
      "C. It has people.",
      "D. It has liquid water",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What makes planet Earth habitable?",
    answer: "D. All of the above",
    options: [
      "A. It has comfortable distance from the sun.",
      "B. It has atmosphere that protects from radiation.",
      "C. The atmosphere holds carbon dioxide and other gases.",
      "D. All of the above",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Why is Earth called a terrestrial planet?",
    answer: "B. It is closest to the sun.",
    options: [
      "A. It has life.",
      "B. It is closest to the sun.",
      "C. It is farther from the sun.",
      "D. It is placed at almost the middle planets.",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following best describes the surface of the planet Earth?",
    answer: "D. mostly water surface with some areas of land",
    options: [
      "A. a thick layer of hydrogen gas",
      "B. cloudy and hot with lots of volcano",
      "C. cold, rocky, and covered with red dust",
      "D. mostly water surface with some areas of land",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Earth is said to be a unique planet. Which answer verifies the statement?",
    answer: "D. All of the above",
    options: [
      "A. It supports life.",
      "B. It is mostly covered in water.",
      "C. Its atmosphere is mostly nitrogen and oxygen.",
      "D. All of the above",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which is supported and sustained by planet?",
    answer: "A. life",
    options: [
      "A. life",
      "B. a moon",
      "C. a rocky core",
      "D. an atmosphere",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "How many percent of water comprises the Earth?",
    answer: "D. 70%",
    options: [
      "A. 15%",
      "B. 30%",
      "C. 50%",
      "D. 70%",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which factors are needed for organisms to live on Earth?",
    answer: "D. both A and B",
    options: [
      "A. temperature and nutrient",
      "B. atmosphere and energy",
      "C. only A",
      "D. both A and B",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "What characteristics does the Earth have to maintain an organism’s body to survive?",
    answer: "D. All of the above",
    options: [
      "A. Earth has a water cycle and atmosphere.",
      "B. Earth has volcanic activities to circulate nutrients.",
      "C. Earth has sub-surface water or molten rock that can circulate and replenish nutrients for organisms.",
      "D. All of the above",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "What makes Earth similar to Venus?",
    answer: "D. Both A and C",
    options: [
      "A. Earth and Venus are the right sizes to hold a sufficient atmosphere.",
      "B. Venus’ atmosphere is 100 times thicker than Earth.",
      "C. Among all the solid planets and moons, only Earth, Venus, and Titan have significant atmospheres.",
      "D. Both A and C",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Which statement about the Earth’s energy in sustaining life is incorrect?",
    answer: "A. Earth survives in too little energy.",
    options: [
      "A. Earth survives in too little energy.",
      "B. Earth is in the right distance from the sun",
      "C. Earth is kept warm by an insulating atmosphere.",
      "D. Earth has magnetic field to protect from solar radiation.",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which distinct characteristic made Earth different from any other planet?",
    answer: "C. It is the only planet that has a large amount of liquid water.",
    options: [
      "A. It is the only rocky planet.",
      "B. It is the only planet that turns around in space.",
      "C. It is the only planet that has a large amount of liquid water.",
      "D. It is the only planet that changes its structure.",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "What does Earth offer to human in order to sustain life?",
    answer: "D. Both A and B",
    options: [
      "A. Earth has abundant plant life.",
      "B. Earth has sufficient nutrients from ocean to land.",
      "C. Only A",
      "D. Both A and B",
    ],
  },
];
